San Francisco, CA, USA

# Summary\_

Experienced firmware developer and M.Eng. graduate from Cornell University in Electrical and Computer Engineering. Interests span from creating and programming

Embedded Systems to Computer Architecture and ASIC design. Experienced with both embedded Linux platforms such as the Raspberry Pi and DE1-SoC, and bare-metal platforms like the PIC32. Well-versed in C, Python and Verilog, and uses Git for version control.

## Education

**Cornell University** Ithaca NY

M.Eng. in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Aug. 2016 - Aug. 2017

- GPA: 3 673
- · Relevant Courses: Advanced Computer Architecture, Embedded Operating Systems, HL Digital Design Automation, Complex Digital ASIC Design, Advanced Microcontroller Design, Parallel Programming

**Cornell University** Ithaca, NY

B.S. IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Aug. 2012 - May 2016

- · Minor: Computer Science
- Dean's List: Spring 2014, Fall 2015, Spring 2016
- · Relevant Courses: Computer Architecture, Designing with Microcontrollers, Digital VLSI Design, Telecommunications, Operating Systems, Embedded Systems

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**Spansive** San Bruno, CA

FIRMWARE DEVELOPER

Jan. 2018 - Present

- · I operate within a small team designing algorithms and utilizing signal processing in order to achieve orientation and position independent wireless charging under the Qi specification.
- The main microcontroller on our board is an NXP KV5x with ARM Cortex M7, programmed with C
- I spearheaded transition to RTOS from bare-metal in order to more readily address the challenges of a complex system, and continue to work with and maintain said system
- I work closely with hardware team during bring-up and debugging of board revisions.
- · I am the sole maintainer of Python testing and verification suite used to characterize properties of the analog circuitry.
- · I implemented our PCB and full assembly tests for manufacturing, and worked with the team at our CM to create the interface with the testing platform.

## **Cornell College of Engineering**

Ithaca, NY

GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT FOR DIGITAL VLSI DESIGN

Jan. 2017 - May 2017

- Held weekly office hours to assist students with concepts and problem sets.
- · Graded problem sets and exams. Graded live demos of lab assignments; these assignments were using Cadence to design specific digital
- · Wrote problems for problem sets and exams. Test drove several labs to verify feasibility.

#### **Cornell Information Technology**

Ithaca, NY

May 2013 - Dec. 2016

· Supervised the use of various computer labs across campus.

- Provided technical support for lab patrons.
- Ensured that the printers were stocked and operational.
- · Prepared specialty classrooms for professors.

#### **Cornell Academic Technologies Center**

Ithaca, NY

STUDENT TECHNOLOGY ASSISTANT

COMPUTER LAB OPERATOR

May 2013 - May 2016

- Provided technical support to professors for various pieces of software.
- Checked out devices such as cameras to professors.
- Performed media conversions (analog to digital) for professors.

APRIL 4, 2019 WILLIAM ABAJIAN · RÉSUMÉ Clad Network, Inc.

Ithaca, NY

LEAD HARDWARE ENGINEER Oct. 2014 - Sept. 2015

- Early employee in startup
- Discussed business and technology strategy with the rest of the team.
- Implemented adaptive lighting system for our product on an Arduino microntroller.
- Created a networking solution for the onboard embedded Linux platform in our product.

## **Wallaby Yogurt Company**

ENGINEERING AND MAINTENANCE INTERN

- Maintained and updated an Access database used for parts inventory.
- Setup virtual environments for testing database software.
- Devised a mobile monitoring system for the plant.
- Performed maintenance on the video surveillance system and the wireless network.
- Assisted in the installation of automation hardware.

Napa County, CA June 2014 - July 2014

APRIL 4, 2019 WILLIAM ABAJIAN · RÉSUMÉ